- BOY: You get them.
- MAN: You take those two.
- And you get them.
- That's it. the job's a good 'un.
Come on...
Get a wriggle on!
He'll be here any minute.
- We mustn't keep Daddy waiting!
- BOY GIGGLES
Oliver!
- Honestly...
- Go on. skedaddle.
[HE GASPS]
Oi!
- I don't know which of you is worse.
- Definitely him. He started it.
No. it's Dad.
Stephen...
Daddy's here.
Stephen.
Bill.
- Can I get you a drink?
- Oh. thanks.
Well. the others should be along
shortly.
Just firing up the old barbecue.
[LIGHTER CLICKS]
- Here you go.
- Oh. ta. love.
You shouldn't have gone
to so much trouble.
- Oh. come on. it's no trouble.
- Yeah.
It's not every day you retire.
Yes.
Well. cheers.
Cheers.
LAUGHTER. CHATTER AND MUSIC
Hiya.
Hey.
It won't be the same without you. Dad.
Mm.
It's not like I'm going to disappear.
No. of course you're not.
- [LIGHTER CLICKS]
- The bloody thing keeps going out.
I. er... I wanted
to pick your brains. actually.
About the Breakwater account.
Any questions about the business.
take them up with Stephen.
He's running things now.
Well. it's just that...
- Come here. let me do it.
- Oh. no. no. it's all right. Bill.
I've got it. it's just...
[HE CLICKS THE LIGHTER ONCE]
[FIRE WHOOSHES]
There.
Thanks. Thanks. Bill.
Well done. Daddy.
[HE SIGHS]
[DOORBELL CHIMES]
Hi. Is your dad in?
Dad!
- There's somebody at the door.
- I'm a bit busy here. mate.
No. but it's a delivery.
Maybe it's a present or something.
Come on. then.
Rose. just keep an eye on that
for a sec.
All right.
- Stephen Marshbrook?
- Yes.
- Hi. Have you got something for me?
[MUFFLED GUNSHOT]
[MUFFLED GUNSHOTS]
Synced & corrected by -robtor-
www.addic7ed.com
I'm sorry to drag you out
over a bit of lead.
but they've stripped the lot.
We've only just had it redone.
We had to have a charity auction
last time.
- Everybody rallied round.
- Mm.
- We can't ask them again.
- I know.
Look. we'll go through the CCTV
and we'll put the word out.
But the chances of us finding them...
I'm sorry. love. I'm just being honest.
[SHE SIGHS]
[LOCK BEEPS AND CLICKS]
- Hi. Lisa.
- Hey.
Who pissed in your porridge?
You try climbing through pigeon shit
on the roof of the Alhambra.
see how you like it.
Just another scintillating day
in the life of a community copper.
Yeah. it's still police work. Lisa.
Somebody's got to do it.
- I know. boss. I didn't mean to...
- Boss?
- Can I have a word?
- Yeah.
Brilliant.
Come on. Leese. The boss knows
you've done your time.
It won't be long now.
Get back out there...
back in the saddle.
She thinks she knows it all now.
now that she's a big-time detective.
Mm-hm.
- [LAUGHTER]
- Yes. all right.
Yes. yes. yes.
Aw...
- Who's your mate?
- A present from the Al Shamis.
Just to say thank you.
I said there's no need. but...
No. I'm going to declare it.
I know the rules. that you're not
allowed to accept gifts from...
Listen. I wasn't going to say a word.
I think you make a lovely couple.
Shooting at a house on Williamson Road.
One fatality.
Med. with me. now.
Lisa...
Come on. then. get a shift on.
[SIREN WAILS]
When you get in the house.
Med takes the lead.
- What he says goes. All right?
- Boss.
Med. she's on probation.
If she sets one foot wrong.
I want to know about it.
[CAR STARTS]
[SIRENS WAIL]
Can you move back. folks?
- Family?
- Around the back. boss.
Get this tented off.
[SOBBING]
- I want statements from everyone.
- Sure.
After you.
- I have to see to it!
- Rose. that'll do! Stop it!
- But I have to clean him up.
- You can't.
I can't just leave him like that!
Rose. please. listen to them.
I'm sorry. they're right. You can't.
You have to leave it.
Forensics will need to... I'm sorry.
Come on. let's sit you down.
There. that's better. OK?
I'm Med and this is Lisa.
We're going to be
your Family Liaison Officers.
Can I just get everybody's names.
please?
Yes.
Yes. of course. I'm Mark.
Bill Bradwell. Med. was it?
This is my daughter. Rose.
My son. Mark.
My daughter-in-law. Stella.
This is my grandson. Oliver.
And the victim?
Er... Stephen.
My husband.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
Hi. Oliver.
I'm Lisa.
He was there.
He saw it happen.
[ROSE SNIFFLES]
[DOOR OPENS]
I've arranged for the family
to be moved.
There's an ABE suite on standby.
Boss...
The Wi-Fi cable's been cut.
And the alarm system. too.
Whoever it was.
they knew what they were doing.
[CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKS]
Rose...
Rose. we're going to need your
permission to take his clothes.
Oh. yeah. Yes. of course.
Erm. and can I just ask.
is there anybody else.
a family member perhaps. who could
act as Oliver's appropriate adult?
Er. I'm sorry?
So. it's just for when
we interview him. cos he's underage.
- Yeah. but I'm his mum.
- No. I know. but it's...
The thing is. we're gonna have
to interview you. too.
So. you can't actually stay
with him. I'm sorry.
No. no. I can't...
- I can't just leave him.
- Rose...
Rose. he's not going to be
on his own. I promise you.
I promise you.
I'm gonna have a social worker
sit in with him.
I know some really. really good ones.
I just need to make a couple of calls.
- OK?
- Yeah.
Come on.
He hasn't spoken.
Hasn't said a word. Hasn't cried. even.
The social worker's arrived.
- We're gonna need specialist help.
- What was that?
MED: No. no. it was just Lisa.
I think we should keep things contained
and keep numbers to a minimum.
It's not a job for Social.
We need a child psychologist.
- Thanks. Lisa. I'm on top of it.
- She's right.
I'll get that sorted.
You two focus on the others for now.
- Preliminary interviews.
- Boss.
Look. I'm not trying to step on your
toes. but the kid needs some help.
Let's just get on with it. yeah?
Do you have any idea
who might have done this. Rose?
No. No.
Did Stephen have anyone
that had a grudge against him?
No. he was just an ordinary man.
We...
It was just a party.
It was just a barbecue.
It's all right.
He was an only child...
...Stephen.
Mum and Dad are both dead.
We were the only family he had.
I suppose.
They have three kids. him and Rose.
There's Oliver. the youngest.
And there's Jamie.
He's just finished university.
He was meant to start work. but...
...decided to take a year off.
backpacking round Europe.
Anyway. he's...
He's on his way home now.
And then there's Grace.
But. er...
...we don't see her any more.
Why not?
Hm.
It's a long story.
[SHOUTS. CAMERA SHUTTERS CLICK]
Oh!
- No rest for the wicked.
- Oh...
Oh! It's for our Muna.
- How did you get on?
- Er. good.
Yeah. we're starting
to build relationships.
get a sense of the lay of the land.
so...
And what about Lisa. how was she?
Did she follow your lead?
Yeah. she was...
- What?
- Fine.
- No. It's just...
It's nothing.
Look. I mean...
She's really good at her job.
she's just...
I hear you.
Leave it with me.
[LOUD MUSIC]
[SHE GROANS]
Turn it the fuck down!
Why should I?
Er. A. because it's too loud.
B. because I'm trying to study.
And C. because it is absolute shit!
Guys. guys. come on...
Rob. turn it down!
I can't hear myself think here!
I hate this place!
[DOOR SLAMS]
- Kids these days...
- Yeah. Tell me about it.
He does have a point. though.
Oh. love. come on.
don't you start and all.
- Mum. I'm not. It's just. I mean...
- Well. I'm trying!
I'm doing my best.
I know it's not ideal.
I didn't want to move here
any more than you did.
But. you know. we are where we are.
At least until I get my stripes back.
I know.
OK. Stephen Marshbrook was
a solicitor for a family law firm.
His wife. Rose. runs the office.
And her brother Mark works there. too.
Now. the business was set up
by Rose and Mark's dad. Bill Bradwell.
But he's recently retired.
His wife died some years ago.
The firm deals in family law.
Wills. conveyancing. property.
Not criminal law.
They're well known and respected
in the community.
So. why would Stephen Marshbrook
have been murdered.
on his own doorstep.
in front of his young son?
Med...
Stephen and Rose have three kids.
So. we have Oliver.
He's the youngest. He's ten.
And then there's Jamie. 21.
Just graduated from university.
And Grace. 23.
Now. her grandad says
she's a bit of a tearaway.
Had a run-in with the police
a few years back.
She was arrested for TDA in 2013.
Nicked her grandad's car.
Yeah. but he refused to press charges.
so she just got off with a caution.
And it caused a breakdown in the family.
She stormed out.
hasn't spoken to them since.
Oh. and we've no idea where she is.
We need to track her down.
Make it a priority.
The only witness we have
to the shooting itself
is the victim's son. Oliver.
But he's still too traumatised to talk.
We have a specialist
child psychologist arriving today.
So. Med. I need you to continue
working with the rest of the family.
But first. let's get Rose
into safe accommodation.
Stu. Eddie. let's expand the parameters
of the house-to-house and CCTV.
We also need to get a briefing
out to the press. Karen.
And the postmortem
is scheduled for this morning.
When we recover the rounds.
we'll get some indication
of the murder weapon.
- So...
- Sorry.
Boss. sorry to interrupt.
Just. er. what did you want me to do?
I've been developing
quite a good relationship with Rose.
So.
maybe I could help Med with the FLO...
No. Erm. Med can handle that.
I want you to go to the law firm. Lisa.
Talk to the rest of the staff.
Was Stephen involved
in any disputes at work?
Did he have any rivals. any...
...any pissed off clients. any enemies?
Who would want to take out
a professional hit
on this seemingly ordinary man?
All right?
You've got your actions. let's go.
Try not to shag anyone this time.
[LAUGHTER]
I'll catch you up.
[DOORBELL BUZZES]
I'm sorry. we're closed.
DC Armstrong. West Lancashire Police.
Could I just have a word?
- Yeah. of course.
- That's great. thank you.
So. you weren't at the party
yourself. Lyn?
No. I wasn't invited.
I'm new. I've only been
with the firm six months.
It was more of a family thing.
Could you just talk me through
what everyone does in the firm?
Erm...
Rose. Stephen's wife.
she's office manager. part-time.
She's very... organised.
Keeps us all on our toes.
OK. What about Mark?
Mark does a lot of the day-to-day
business with the clients.
A lot of the stuff
Stephen wouldn't have time for.
Wait. so does...?
Sorry. did Mark work for Stephen?
No.
Not exactly.
Mark's not a partner.
Whereas. Stephen was a senior...
...partner.
Sorry.
Look. Lyn. I'm sorry.
I have to ask. Erm...
Is there anyone that had
a grievance against Stephen?
You know. a client or.
I don't know. a business rival?
No.
Everyone liked him.
No-one had a bad word to say about him.
I can't understand it.
- I can't believe it.
- Hello?
Sorry. Mark. er...
- This is. er...
- Oh. it's DC Armstrong.
- I was at the house yesterday.
- Yes.
Yes. of course. Look...
I'm afraid this really
isn't a good time.
We want to help.
But not today. Everyone's in shock.
Yes. of course. Of course.
That's fine. I'll leave you in peace.
Thank you so much for your help.
Lyn. and we'll be in touch.
OK.
[DOOR CLOSES]
- Look. why don't you go home?
- No.
No. I want to help. I want to keep busy.
Lyn... it's fine. go home.
[PHONE RINGS]
Hey. Everything all right?
Yeah. everything's fine.
I just heard on the radio
about that murder.
- I can't talk about work. Mum.
- No. I know.
But the thing is. I know him.
I mean. I knew him.
[SEATBELT CLICKS]
- Where are you now?
- I'm at work. at the shop.
OK. I'm on my way.
Yeah. if you want to talk to her.
you might have to. you know. use words.
Who said I want to talk to her?
[THEY CHUCKLE]
They did your dad's will.
They took care of everything
when he died.
- And you got to know Stephen?
- Well. not much. but he was around.
I'm sorry.
I mostly dealt with the older man. Bill.
He was a bit odd.
- How do you mean?
- Just...
I don't know.
there was something hard about him.
Not somebody that you would warm to.
OK. What about Stephen?
He seemed OK. He seemed nice.
Sorry. it's probably not much use.
I just thought you should know.
in case it's something that
you need to declare or whatever.
No. it's fine. Mum.
Sorry. can I ask how much this is?
Only. I've not got my reading glasses.
I'll leave you to it.
If you think of anything else.
give me a shout.
- Oh. OK. love. Yeah. that's £10.
- Oh.
Lisa...
I know you're really busy
with work and everything.
So. er. if you need any help at home.
if you want me to come
and give the kids their tea...
We're fine. Mum. Honestly.
OK. because I know it isn't easy.
- Abbie's got her exams and Rob's...
- We're fine. We're managing.
OK. Good! That's good.
Are you OK?
Oh. you know me. the same old. same old.
OK.
Are you all right?
- Right. let's go.
- Thank you.
Thank you.
Right...
Why don't you get settled in?
PC Rowley will be just out here as well.
Why?
- Why do I need an armed guard?
- No. no. it's just...
It's all routine.
When a firearm's been involved.
it's standard procedure.
I should be with Oliver.
I should never have left him on his own.
No. no. he's not on his own. Rose.
He's only ten!
He's never even spent a night
away from home before.
- He's never even been on a sleepover!
- Rose. I promise you.
We are looking after him. All right?
Just try and get some rest. at least.
As soon as it's possible.
I'll take you to see him.
- SHE SIGHS
- Trust me.
[PHONE RINGS]
Hey.
Hey. Can you do us a favour?
I'll clear it with the boss.
[KNOCK ON THE DOOR]
Hey. Rose.
- [DOOR CLOSES]
- How are you getting on?
I. er...
[SHE EXHALES]
I...
[SHE SOBS]
Hey. it's all right.
It's all right.
He was like a son to me.
My right-hand man.
He was.
[HE SOBS]
I'm sorry.
No.
- No. don't be. it's...
- Grandad?
- Oh. Grandad...
- Jamie!
Where's Mum?
Well. she's not answering the phone.
We went to the house. they wouldn't
let us anywhere near it.
- Where is she?
- Yeah. I'll take you to her.
I'm sorry.
I'm making such a show of myself.
Oh. come on. don't be daft.
That's what he'd say.
- Stephen?
- No.
No. my dad.
He'd say. "You have to be strong."
He'd say. "You have to pull yourself
together." And he's right.
No. come on. now.
You've just lost your husband.
It's OK to be upset.
It's OK to be broken. you've...
I'm sure your dad would understand that.
Yeah. of course.
[KNOCK ON THE DOOR]
Mum!
[SHE GASPS]
Oh!
[SHE LAUGHS TEARFULLY]
Theo...
Thank you.
- Thank you for coming.
- No. it's...
I'm sorry. Mum.
I shouldn't have gone away.
I should've been here.
Oh. no. you're here now.
That's the main thing.
- Has Grace been in touch?
- She hasn't made contact?
We don't even know where she is.
I do.
I know where she is.
Can we get any better images than that?
- I can try for sure.
- Yeah. just a minute. I'm. erm...
Boss. we think we've found Grace.
She's working at a scrapyard
outside Barrow.
Well. if Grace is still in the area.
why hasn't she come forward?
She's bound to have heard.
Anything else on the family?
Yeah. Er. Jamie's arrived back now.
too. with his partner Theo.
Erm. I also talked to Bill.
He's the SPOC.
Now. he says the family was tightknit.
And statements from the other guests
at the party.
they tend to bear this out.
So. aside from the Grace thing.
they do paint a picture
of one big. happy family. really.
Are you sure about that. though?
Just...
...I've been getting the impression
that all wasn't well in the business.
There seem to be tensions
around the fact that Stephen
was a partner and Mark wasn't.
And I'm sensing something
just not quite right
in Rose's relationship with her dad.
- OK.
- Right.
No. no. sorry. sorry. boss.
that's not how the family sees it.
Well. they're not going to just come
right out and say that. are they?
Just. if Bill's the SPOC.
we might want to think about...
Sorry. I have to interrupt you there.
I'm really sorry. Lisa.
but with all due respect...
...I've spent time with him.
I've been in the house.
getting to know him. so I...
It's not a question of time. is it?
It's knowing what to look for.
- So what should I be looking for?
- All right. that'll do. you two.
- That's enough.
- Yeah.
Sorry.
Stu...
Er. yeah. We've been going through CCTV.
The Marshbrooks' house
is on a cul-de-sac.
We've checked all the traffic
in and out on the day of the murder
and the only vehicle
we haven't been able
to account for is this one.
A blue Fiat van from a courier
service called PDD.
Yeah. we've spoken to the company
and there were no deliveries
scheduled for that day in the area.
And the plates don't match
any of their vehicles.
They do. however.
match those of a Vauxhall Corsa
reported stolen eight days ago
in Salford.
It looks like this... is our killer.
- Boss. the thing is...
- No. no. I don't want to hear it.
A man's lost his life.
You know. we're all under pressure here.
Whatever shit
you've got going on between you.
you put it to one side
and you do your job.
Do I make myself clear?
- Yes. sir.
- Yes. boss. I'm sorry.
I thought I told you. Lisa.
Med takes the lead.
What he says goes.
But she's right. You need to dig deeper.
If there's bad blood in this family.
we need to know about it.
You need to pull your finger out here.
Med.
No. don't blame Med.
I shouldn't have flown off
the handle. It won't happen again.
Well. it better bloody not.
It's my neck on the line here. too.
you know.
Do you not think I've got enough
on my plate without this?
Now. go on. the pair of you.
And talk to Grace for a kick-off.
Find out what's going on in this family.
- Do your job.
- Sir.
- I'll see you later.
- See you later.
Whoa. watch where you're going!
I heard that crack earlier.
at the briefing.
It was just a joke. Leese.
Lighten up. fuck's sake.
Lighten up?
I was only pissing about.
You weren't just pissing about. though.
You were questioning my
ability to do my job.
You were trying to undermine me
in front of the entire team.
You should've thought
about that before...
Go on. before what? Go on.
- You know what.
- Lisa...
I have been demoted. I've been fined.
I've had to sell my house.
I'm living in a bloody shoebox
with my kids.
Whatever I did.
I've more than made up for it!
Lisa...
You don't half choose your moments.
I know.
Wanker.
Can I help you?
- Yeah.
- Yeah. erm...
Detective Sergeant Kharim.
And this
is Detective Constable Armstrong.
- And you are?
- Frank Mercer.
I'm the gaffer here.
What can I do for you?
We're looking for Grace Marshbrook.
- Why?
- It's all right. Frank.
Listen. we're. er...
We're sorry to have to meet like
this. under these circumstances.
You have heard about your dad?
Of course I have. How's Oliver?
Yeah. yeah. yeah.
He's being looked after.
And you haven't been in touch
with the family?
Why's that?
We don't talk.
How come?
Well. you're the police.
It's all on file. I expect.
Well. we'd like to hear your side
of the story.
They made it perfectly clear
they want nothing to do with me.
so I want nothing to do with them.
Even now?
Even now.
Where were you yesterday afternoon?
You've got...
You've got to be kidding me?
No.
I was here. I was working.
You can ask Frank.
You can ask any of them.
They'll tell you.
There you go.
Yesterday's deliveries.
She signed for them.
Thank you. OK.
So. you'll vouch for her. will you?
I don't have to. do I?
It's there in black and white.
- But. yeah. I will. as it goes.
- OK.
She was here all day with me.
Right. thank you.
It was awful. what happened.
But she had nothing to do with it.
She has nothing to do with her family.
Thanks.
Well?
I have her signature on the delivery
note at 15:00 on the day.
Yeah. but just because
she didn't pull the trigger.
it doesn't mean she didn't set it up.
We can't rule her out.
But we don't have enough
to take her in. either.
Listen. erm...
...about earlier.
This is your case. Med. I just...
I just want to do my job. mate.
So... what now. boss?
We dig deeper.
OK.
[PHONE RINGS]
What's wrong?
Nothing's wrong.
Look. I...
I know I'm not supposed to phone you
when you're at work.
but I just want to say
I'll be home late tonight.
- Oh. yeah? And why's that. then?
- Cos I got a job.
Waitressing at The Beach Cafe.
Abbie. you've got your exams.
I know. but it's just in the evenings.
Love. you don't have to do this.
We'll manage.
Mum. I... I want to.
OK.
You should go and see them.
No.
They obviously don't want me there.
Let's just get back to work.
Ooph! Some guard dog you are.
I don't know what you're talking about!
Hello?
They were here last week. Bill.
You liked it.
Just give them a chance.
- What are they doing in my house?
- Dad...
We talked about this.
Bill. we agreed you'd do this.
I didn't agree to anything!
- Now. go on. bugger off!
- [THEY GASP]
I can make my dinner. thank you.
I'm not completely bloody useless!
I'm sorry. is this not a good time?
And what was that about?
It's just a new arrangement
and he forgets sometimes.
He thinks he can look after himself.
He thinks he's still 100%.
But he's just getting more muddled.
- So. what do you mean. he thinks...
- I can hear you. you know!
I'm not deaf.
No. no.
we were just having a chat. Bill.
I don't know.
People traipsing round my house.
As if I didn't have enough
to contend with.
As if...
Go on.
Get out of my home.
I think you should probably go.
[FRONT DOOR CLOSES]
'It's OK if you don't feel like talking.
'Sometimes. I don't feel like talking.
'But there's loads of other things
we can do.'
- How did you get on?
- [HE SIGHS]
Not great. Bill.
He wasn't in a fit state to talk.
Well. he's grieving.
I... I think it's more than that.
Anyway. how about you?
How's Oliver doing?
Still nothing. not a word.
Look... maybe if we could just make
it a bit more homely.
If he had his familiar things
around him.
it might just help him open up.
you know.
And maybe
if he had his mum with him. too?
Yeah.
- Are you all right. Dave?
- Hey.
- Can I get through?
- You'll have to go round the back.
OK. cheers. mate.
[CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKS]
- Have you found something. mate?
- Some papers in the ashes.
Right. we've got nothing useful
from the text. I'm afraid.
But the logo's clear.
So. it's possible
that Stephen's just used work paper
to light the barbecue.
But realistically?
- Ah. look who it is!
- Sorry. I didn't mean to interrupt.
Oh. don't be daft. It's only me.
How are you?
- Yeah. I'm good. thanks.
- Yeah...
Just. er...
- Lisa. er. could you just...
- Yeah. Sorry. yeah. of course.
Good to see you. Ellen.
- Bye. Lisa.
- Bye. Ellen. See you.
- Are you all right?
- Er. yeah.
Come on. let's go and see him.
When can he come home?
I mean. not "home" home. but...
Yeah. it's going to take us
a few more days.
but we're moving as quickly as we can.
We're talking to the school. yeah?
And we're going to make sure
every measure's put in place.
[KNOCK ON THE DOOR]
Hiya.
I just brought some of your stuff.
Oliver.
Now. I just grabbed
whatever I could see.
so if you need anything else.
just let me know. OK?
Thank you.
Oliver...
Hello. Rob.
We need to make arrangements.
find them somewhere to stay
in the longer term.
They can't stay in that hotel
indefinitely.
- Sorry. do you mind if I just?
- Sure.
Thank you. Cheers.
Can you just give me a minute?
[DOOR OPENS]
[DOOR CLOSES]
[KNOCK ON THE DOOR]
Hi.
Hey...
Can I see?
What's that?
A bird with two heads.
Oh. yeah.
Yeah. I see it now. That's really good.
Thank you.
Why are you drawing
a bird with two heads?
Have you seen it somewhere before?
[HE EXHALES]
Oliver?
Have you?
Where have you seen it?
The man had it.
Here.
Like a tattoo?
Yeah.
What man. Oliver? What man?
The man who shot Dad.
OK. mate.
I'll get Stu to go through the database.
see if he can find a match
for the tattoo.
Good work.
Both of you.
So. how did it go?
It were bloody knackering.
[SHE LAUGHS]
Welcome to my world!
- Stick the kettle on.
- Right...
Hey?
So. don't freak out.
All right. love?
Dad...